northumbria.ac.uk 2019-03-31

# Cookies

### 1.Data Controller

**Registration Number: Z7674926**

**University of Northumbria at Newcastle** (“we”, “our”, “us”) processes personal data in accordance with our obligations under the General Data Protection Regulations (‘GDPR’) and is a registered Data Controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office (‘ICO’), which is the supervisory authority responsible for the oversight and enforcement of Data Protection Legislation within the United Kingdom. 

### 2.Overview

We are committed to protecting the privacy of all individuals. For purposes of this Privacy Notice, personal data means any information about an identifiable individual. Personal data excludes anonymous or de-identified data that is not associated with a particular individual.

This privacy notice is a statement that describes how and why we processes personal data in relation to any individual (“you”, “your”) visiting any of Websites owned or operated by us that link to this page. It does not cover third party websites that you may access from links on our website(s), so when opening pages that take you away from our sites, you should exercise caution. 

This notice also explains how you might control the use of your personal data in accordance with your rights under the GDPR. You may be given further information about the uses of personal data when accessing specific services and facilities.

### 3.Where do we get your personal data from and what data is collected? 

You may provide us with some of your information directly when you use any of our online forms, for example to make an enquiry, submit request to register of an open day, or to subscribe to receive email marketing communications such as online newsletters. Examples of personal data we may process include:

**Category** | **Example**  
---|---  
Biographical information | Name, title, birth date, age and gender, interests  
Administrative | Contact details, event applications etc  
Historical  | Your employment or academic history  
  
Some form you may use could ask you to submit credit/debit card details. In this case you be aware that the University is fully PCI-DSS compliant.

Where you submit this information, a relevant Privacy Notice associated with the processing will be made available to you. 

We will only collect personal information, e.g. name and address where you knowingly supply the information through using on line forms or by sending us an e-mail. 

If you visit protected pages, where to gain access a user ID and password is required, then we also automatically collect the user ID used to access each page.

You may also provide data to us through your use of our website. As with most web servers, our web servers automatically collect the following information:

  * Requested URL (Uniform Resource Locator)
  * IP (Internet Protocol) address (this may or may not identify a specific computer)
  * Domain name from which you access the internet
  * Referring URL
  * Software (browser/operating system) used to access the page

### 4.Activities we process your personal data

Data is required for the following activities, which have been identified as necessary “necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party” as the information you provide is used by us as follows:  

  * We will use the information collected to monitor traffic, helping us to measure the effectiveness of our Web Site and to plan for new developments. This data is processed anonymously.

  * We will only use the personal information, which you supply, for those purposes described at the point of collection or for those purposes, which are legally permitted. We may use this information to contact you, at a later date, with details of news and events relevant to your original request providing we have your consent. If you choose not to give consent, we will only use your personal information to respond to your enquiry.

  * We will also analyse how you interact with this website, such as the pages you visit and what elements you interact with, this will then be used to provide you with personalised content to enhance your user experience and help us to improve the website.  Non-personal information such as you IP address will used to determine your general location to provide personalised information. 

  * We will only disclose your personal information to third parties (i.e. people or organisations outside Northumbria University) in ways which are permitted by this Statement or when required by law, e.g. to comply with a Court Order.

Our websites use ’cookies’, which are text files placed on your computer when you visit a site which help us understand how you use our websites. Some of our cookies remain on your computer after you leave the website, others are deleted automatically when you close your browser and others expire after a given period. The following table provides a list of the cookies used on our website along with information about how long they will remain active for, and or how you can disable them manually. Please note Northumbria University does not control dissemination of 3rd party cookies you should check the relevant third party website for more information about these. 

**Name**

| 

**Cookie type**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Sitecore 

(1st Party)

| 

Necessary and functional cookies

| 

The Sitecore cookies enable you to use functions of the site such as favourite pages, recent pages and course comparison. The cookies also identify repeat visits helping us tailor our content and user experience.

SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_COOKIE Randomly generated identifier assigned to a visitor to help identify returning visits to the site. Expires one year after creation.

SC_ANALYTICS_SESSION_COOKIE Randomly generated identifier assigned to a visitor to help identify visits across a session on the site. Expires within 30 minutes of the browser closing.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media or do not accept cookies from when our disclaimer appears on the website.  
  
Salesforce Pardot  
(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

Pardot is a marketing automation tool developed by Salesforce inc. Pardot uses cookies to track visitors and potential student applicant activities on our website and within the application portal by setting cookies on their browsers.  Cookie duration:3650 days.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media or do not accept cookies from when our disclaimer appears on the website.  
  
Google Analytics (3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

This collects information about how visitors use the website, to be able to compile reports and make improvements to better meet our users' needs.

The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. Two cookies are used _ga to distinguish users and expire in 2 years, _gat is used to throttle request rates and expire in 10 minutes. 

**How do I disable this Cookie?**[ Opt out add-on for Google Analytics](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)  
  
Google Analytics (3rd Party)

| 

Targeting cookies

| 

We use Google Analytics Audience Demographics and Interest Reporting within Google Analytics to further our audience understanding so we can improve our content, retargeting and user experience accordingly. 

**How do I disable this Cookie?**[ Opt out of Google’s interest advertising](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/anonymous)  
  
Disqus 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

To post comments on pages that allow comments we use Disqus as a service to facilitate online discussions. 

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media.  
  
AddThis 

(3rd Party)

| 

Targeting cookies

| 

We use AddThis, a popular social bookmarking toolbar, to allow you to share content via social media sites including Facebook and Twitter.

It uses cookies to find out how pages are shared so we can find out what our visitors like. It may also use that data to deliver tailored advertising on other websites you go on to visit.

When you share content via social media, these sites may set a cookie if you are also logged in to their service. We don't control third party cookies but we recommend you visit the relevant websites for more information.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**[ AddThis privacy information](http://www.addthis.com/privacy)and[opt out option](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out)  
  
Google Conversion Tracking (3rd Party)

| 

Targeting cookies

| 

We use conversion tracking to understand user behaviour and to improve our site. The Googleadservices.com cookies help website owners who buy ads from Google to determine how many people who click their ads end up purchasing their products. The conversion tracking cookie is set on your browser only when you click an ad delivered by Google where the advertiser has opted in to conversion tracking.

These cookies expire within 30 days and do not contain information that can identify you personally. If this cookie has not yet expired when you visit certain pages of the advertiser's website, Google and the advertiser will be able to tell that you clicked the ad and proceeded to that page. Each advertiser gets a different cookie, so no cookie can be tracked across advertiser websites.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**[ Opt out of Google’s interest advertising](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/anonymous)  
  
DoubleClick 

(3rd Party)

| 

Targeting cookies

| 

The DoubleClick.net cookies allow us to serve our adverts online. We use it to understand behaviour and how users arrive at our site and interact with it. There is no personal identifiable information sent in the tag.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**[ Opt out option](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/anonymous)  
  
YouTube 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

YouTube uses cookies to help maintain the integrity of video statistics and prevent fraud.

We embed some videos on our site from our official YouTube channel; when we do this, we aim to use the privacy-enhanced mode which means YouTube will not set a cookie unless a user clicks to play the video. YouTube cookies contain the count of views of embedded videos.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media  
  
Vimeo 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

When you use a visit a webpage with a Vimeo video, Vimeo may place a number of cookies in your browser. Some of the cookies will only be used if you use certain features or select certain preferences, and some cookies will always be used. 

We embed some videos on our site from our official Vimeo channel.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media   
  
Twitter (3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

We use Twitter to display relevant feeds on our site to enhance our content. Twitter widget data such as page visit and browser information is held within the cookie. Twitter also used logged in status information and may tailor content to improve your experience.[Twitter privacy information and preference options](https://twitter.com/privacy)

**  
How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media.  
  
Facebook 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

We use Facebook to display relevant feeds on our site to enhance our content. Facebook cookies indicate logged in status information to show relevant and social information for the social plugins and services.[Facebook privacy information and opt out options](https://en-gb.facebook.com/help/365596123604315/)

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media.  
  
LinkedIn 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

We use LinkedIn to display relevant feeds on our site to enhance our content. LinkedIn cookies indicate existing user status information and may tailor content accordingly as well as containing page load information.[LinkedIn privacy information and opt out options](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy/)

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media.  
  
Unibuddy 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

We use unibuddy to improve the ease of communication with our users. The cookies is used to identify a user and allow for user personalisation.[Unibuddy privacy information](https://unibuddy.co/terms-and-conditions#Privacy%20Policy)

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media.  
  
Thinglink 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

We use Thinglink to present interactive imagery e.g. maps.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media.  
  
WisePops 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

We use WisePops to provide targeted pop-up information to you on certain webpages. 

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

To opt out please disable cookies from within your browser and remove them from your storage media.  
  
VWO Visual Website Optimiser 

(3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

We use VWO to run tests to determine what design and content will best improve your experience. VWO uses cookies to run tests and to track user information. The cookies keep track of the variation a user has viewed and help to serve the same variation to the user consistently; track goals completed by a user; and determine whether a user is a part of a test. These cookies expire in 100 days. 

**How do I disable this Cookie?**

[More information about VWO Cookie Policy](https://vwo.com/knowledge/what-are-the-cookies-stored-by-vwo/) and [opt out option](https://vwo.com/opt-out/)  
  
Hotjar (3rd Party)

| 

Functional cookies

| 

Hotjar is an analysis and feedback tool that reveals the online behaviour and feedback of website visitors. Examples of the type of information collected include, but is not limited to, pages visited, how pages are used and interacted with, type of device and browser used and the country you are in. Hotjar uses cookies to collect non-personal information.

**How do I disable this Cookie?**[ Hotjar privacy information](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy)and[opt out option](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out)  
  
**Communications**

We will contact you in relation to events and products that we believe are relevant to you based upon their similar nature to your engagement with us including: events, benefits and opportunities offered by us, or in relation to operational information (e.g. building closures etc). 

If, at any stage, you are concerned about the content (e.g. unwanted marketing), frequency (too many) or method (change preference) of these communications, you can unsubscribe or update your preferences using the link which will be provided at the bottom of the relevant correspondence. 

Should you unsubscribe from our marketing messages you will miss regular communications about our services and updates.

### 5.How personal data is stored securely by Northumbria University 

We have implemented appropriate physical, technical, and organisational security measures designed to secure your personal data against accidental loss and unauthorised access, use, alteration, or disclosure. In addition, we limit access to personal data to those employees, agents, contractors, and other third parties that have a legitimate business need for such access. 

All of our employees, contractors and volunteers with access to personal data receive mandatory data protection training and have a contractual responsibility to maintain confidentiality and access to your data is restricted to those members of staff who have a requirement to access it. Your data may be transferred and processed between relevant departments in order to provide you with access to services, to provide you with support or to fulfil the processing activities listed above.

We utilises many different storage solutions and IT systems, some of which are outsourced to third party providers. For example, email accounts are provided by the Microsoft Live@Edu service.

Where processing takes place with an external third party, processing takes place under an appropriate agreement outlining their responsibilities to ensure that processing is compliant with the Data Protection legislation and verified to be secure. 

### 6.Your Rights under GDPR

Under the GDPR, you have a number of rights in relation to the processing of your personal information, each of which may apply to differing degrees’ dependent upon the nature of the processing and the legal basis for it. You have the right to: 

  * Be informed as to how we use your data (via this privacy notice)

  * Request access (a copy) of the personal information that we hold about you. 

  * Correct inaccurate or incomplete data 

  * Request that we stop sending you direct marketing communications.  

In certain circumstances, you may have the right to: 

  * Ask to have your data ‘erased.

  * Request is to restrict the processing of your personal data.  

  * Request that data you provided electronically to us be returned in as a data file 

  * Object to certain processing of your personal data by us  

In some cases, there may be specific exemptions as to why we aren’t able to comply with some of the above. Where this is the case, we will explain the reasons why.  

For more information about any of the above please see the GDPR pages of our website. 

In order to exercise any of the above rights, please contact the Data Protection Officer (details below). 

### 7.Data Protection Officer

The Data Protection Officer for Northumbria University is Duncan James. 

Please do not hesitate to email us at dp.officer@northumbria.ac.uk. If your request is urgent, please call +44 (0)191 243 7357 

### 8.Lodging a Complaint with the Information Commissioners Office (ICO)

If you are dissatisfied with our processing of your data, or a response to a complaint you have made to us about it, you have the right to complain to the ICO. 

Information Commissioner's Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

Telephone: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545 745

Fax: 01625 524 510

For more information see Information [Commissioner’s web site](http://www.ico.org.uk/).

### 9.Changes to this privacy notice

We keep this privacy notice under regular review and will communicate any significant updates to you. This privacy notice was last updated in May 2018 and will be reviewed annually.
